Javad Adib







Full Stack PHP Developer, Software Engineer

Lives 15+ years with code and debugging as a programmer. A microservice architecture lover because of the freedom of technology and scalability. Earn valuable knowledge via teamwork and collaboration with specialists. Built infrastructures of 7+ multi-million dollar projects from scratch. Interested in negotiation and comprehension of customers. A learner who knows how to learn. Extensive wisdom from eCommerce. Open-source enthusiast.

🔀 mr.javad.adib@gmail.com





04/2022 v7.0.1

Professional Experience

Founder, CEO, and Full Stack Developer

Jibres Iran (2 years 5 months) 12/2019 - present

- Provide cloud infrastructure to 1,000+ businesses, integrated eCommerce solution with website, app, PoS software, CMS, CRM, accounting software, ticketing system, form builder.
- Joined the bug bounty program and introduced a new WAF that filters and monitors 99% of the attacks.
- Launched an automated app factory that generated a native android shopping app without coding in less than 10 minutes.

Founder, CEO, and Software Engineer

Ermile Iran (4 years 7 months) 06/2015 - 12/2019

- Raised \$1M from the Angel investor, spearheaded a 15 member cross-functional team to create a Sarshomar that gained about 1M users just a month after launch.
- Constructed an educational management system that serves four organizations, 500,000+ students, and 2,000+ teachers.
- Built Siftal UI framework, Dash as PHP framework with MVC pattern, 2x the development speed by consolidated SPA.

Web UI/UX Designer

Freelancer Iran (6 years 10 months) 09/2008 - 06/2015

- Designed and developed 40+ WordPress websites with HTML5 and CSS3, user experience, and communicated with dozens of customers, including universities, companies, and celebrities.
- Strengthened negotiation skills, mastered sales skills, optimized speed of 10+ websites, achieved high SEO rank.

Computer Lecturer

Teacher Iran (15+ years) 06/2006 - (continued)

- Taught 2,000+ students in web technologies courses, ICDL in 4 universities, vocational colleges, and private classes.
- Created and published tens of hours of unique free web and office video tutorials, which has led to an acquisition of skills by thousands of Persian speakers from around the world.

Volunteer work

DevOps and Frontend Developer

Khadije Charity Iran (4 years 4 months) 12/2017 - 03/2022

 Developed the website and all the software infrastructure to accelerate and fulfilled the wishes of 110,000+ people.

Software Solutions for Business - Expert

WorldSkills Iran Iran (5 years 4 months) 06/2010 - 08/2015

 Tutored and trained three talents who won silver and two bronze medals in national competitions; Held the national team camp to attend WorldSkills Sao Paulo 2015.

Education

M.S. in IT Management

Azad University Tehran, Iran 2015 - 2022

B.S. in Computer Software Engineering

Azad University Nour, Iran

2008 - 2014

Skills

Fully Proficient Web Technology HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP Language C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Node.js, TypeScript, Python, Bash Data Structure and Database MySQL, SQL Server, JSON, YAML Web Service SOAP, REST API, GraphQL

Back-end PHP Web Framework Laravel, Symfony
Front-end JS Library jQuery, Alpine.js, React, Vue.js, Angular
CSS Framework Tailwind, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Materialize

 $\textbf{Build Tool} \ \mathsf{Sass}, \ \mathsf{Grunt}, \ \mathsf{Gulp}, \ \mathsf{Gradle}, \ \mathsf{Webpack}$

Version Control System Git, Github, Gitlab

Test-driven development - TDD PHPUnit

CI/CD Container Docker, Kubernetes Backend Web Server Nginx, Apache

Server Configuration Framework, UI cPanel, DirectAdmin Server Management HPE iLO, VMware ESXi, pfSense Firewall Network DNS, DHCP, HTTP, SSL, TLS, SMTP, FTP, MIME, SSH OS Windows, Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, macOS

Software Development Methodology Scrum, Agile, Kanban Microsoft Office Specialist Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint Graphic Design Tool Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma Miscellaneous Cloud Development, SaaS, Database Design, Algorithm, QA, Object Orientated, A/B Testing, OWASP, CORS, XML, XHTML, Twig, AJAX, PWA, SCSS, NPM, Composer, CLI, LEMP, LAMP, Wireguard, Accounting, Maintenance, VoIP, AWS

Awards and Honors

MembershipIranNational Elites Foundation2013

Silver MedalYazd, Iran
WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Solutions for Business
2009

Medallion for Excellence Mashhad, Iran

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Applications

<u>Languages</u>

English Fluent C1

Persian Native

2008